# Personal Information

Tom F.H. Runia Ph.D. Student runia@uva.nl tomrunia.github.io

University of Amsterdam

I am second-year **Ph.D. student** at the University of Amsterdam, where I am supervised by Cees Snoek and Arnold Smeulders. I work in the fields of computer vision, machine learning and deep learning. The focus of my research is on **understanding video** by learning motion representations. Our **QUVA Deep Vision lab** is a collaboration between the University of Amsterdam and Qualcomm Research.

# Education

### 2016 – Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Computer Science

- QUVA Deep Vision lab: University of Amsterdam and Qualcomm
- Deep Learning for Learning Video Representations
- Advisors: Cees G.M. Snoek and Arnold W.M. Smeulders

# 2013 – 2015 Master of Science (M.S.) in Computer Science

- Delft University of Technology
- Specialization in Intelligent Information Processing
- With Honors, Cum Laude (GPA 8.5/10, A+)

### 2008 – 2012 Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Applied Physics

- Delft University of Technology
- Extra 30 ECTs of B.A. Computer Science courses

# **Employment**

#### 2014 – 2015 Research Intern at TomTom

Computer vision and machine learning scientific internship as part of my Master's thesis on accelerating object detection in autonomous driving context. This involved research and implementation of high-speed computer vision algorithms using C++ and OpenCL.

### 2013 – 2015 **Software Engineer** at **TamTam** (now Dept)

Back-end developer at the Operational Services division where I worked on some of the largest websites in The Netherlands.

### 2012 – 2013 Research Assistant at Delft University of Technology

Assistant in the Quantitative Imaging group at TU Delft where I worked on writing image processing software for super-resolution microscopy.

# 2009 – 2010 Software Engineer at Innovative Design Delft

Part-time back-end developer during my B.S. studies.

# Professional Experience

#### Scientific Publications

- Tom F.H. Runia, Cees G.M. Snoek and Arnold W.M. Smeulders.
  Real-World Repetition Estimation by Div, Grad and Curl.
  Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), June 2018; Spotlight Presentation.
- Tom F.H. Runia, R. Lukassen, L. Zhang and M. Loog.
  The System Design of a High-Speed Object Detector.
  Netherlands Conference on Computer Vision (NCCV), September 2015.

#### **Awards**

• Rewarded the **Ngi-NGN Award** in Computer Science for my MSc. Thesis (€1,000) (*From*: The Royal Holland Society of Sciences and Humanities)

# **Teaching**

- M.S. Course **Deep Learning** at University of Amsterdam (2017)
- B.S. Course Information Visualization at University of Amsterdam (2016)
- Project Supervision of B.S. and M.S. student projects in Artificial Intelligence

# Journal and Conference Reviewing

- PAMI IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (2016, 2017)
- NIPS Neural Information Processing Systems (2016, 2017)
- CVPR Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (2016, 2017)
- ICCV International Conference on Computer Vision (2017)
- ECCV European Conference on Computer Vision (2016)

### **Extracurricular Activities**

- Full-Time Board Member of the Study Association for Applied Physics (2012–2013)
- Entrepreneurial Study Trip to Silicon Valley (visiting Google, Apple, Twitch and more)
- President of the Electronic Committee at the Study Assoc. for Physics (2008–2012)
- Editor of the Quarterly Magazine "De Physics" for the Physics Study Association (2010)